Arijit Sarkar

Hyderabad | rajsarkar170@gmail.com | +919804982448 | LinkedIn | GitHub |

SUMMARY

A software engineer with 3+ years of experience, with 2 years in designing, developing, and maintaining scalable software systems and applications. Experienced Full Stack Developer trained in HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, React, NodeJs and software development methodologies such as Agile and Scrum along with software deployment and maintenance. Built Client Side Product Configuration Screens which led to faster implementation of client-specific configs by 80% and reduced dependency on the Product Team.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer 2 - Stellantis NV Pvt. Ltd. - Hyderabad - Hybrid

July 2022 - May 2024

- Developed and maintained responsive web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React, applied SEO principles for better website rating and search score.
- Implemented RESTful APIs to enable seamless communication between frontend and backend services, improving data retrieval efficiency by 40%.
- Worked in the Product teams of Maserati and led the development of dynamic user interfaces with React, enhancing user engagement and satisfaction of >200000+ clients.
- Utilized Docker for containerization, streamlining development and deployment processes.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams in an Agile environment, contributing to sprint planning, daily stand-ups, and retrospectives.
- Implemented version control and continuous integration using Git, resulting in a 30% reduction in deployment time.

Software Engineer 1- Stellantis NV Pvt. Ltd. - Hybrid

Oct 2021 - July 2022

- Developed and maintained front end components for web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Implemented client-specific configuration screens, reducing implementation time by 80% and increasing client satisfaction by 25%
- Collaborated with designers to create visually appealing and user-friendly web pages, enhancing overall user experience.
- Utilized React to develop dynamic and interactive UI components, improving user engagement by 25%.
- Applied Agile methodologies to manage tasks and deliver features incrementally, contributing to improved team efficiency.
- Leveraged Git for version control, ensuring codebase integrity and facilitating seamless collaboration with team members.

Anon Wellness - Remote Jul-2021 - Oct 2021

- Assisted in the development of web applications using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Collaborated with senior developers to implement responsive design principles, ensuring compatibility across multiple devices.
- Participated in code reviews and contributed to improving code quality and performance.
- Applied SEO principles and ensuring applications adhere to them

SKILLS

- Functional Agile, Jira, SDLC, Confluence
- Technical -HTML,CSS,Bootstrap,Javascript, ReactJs,NodeJs,LLMs,SEO,C++,MySQL,System Design

EDUCATION

Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology - Bhubaneswar

April 2021 - June 2021

B.Tech in Computer Science Engineering - CGPA 7/10

PROJECTS

- Movie Info Website A full-stack movie website where UI was based on CSS,HTML and all the DOM manipulation was
 done using javascript.
- Designed and developed a responsive <u>e-commerce platform</u> using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React using techniques like state management, react router, hooks etc.
- Bind Vendor Seller Application (Freelancing) An <u>application</u> that involves vendors mainly home businesses selling to their customers, having checkout, filter, location search, etc. **Tech Stack Used: HTML,CSS,React,Javascript,SQL.**

HONORS & AWARDS

- Stellar-Performer of the Quarter for Q2, 2022 in Stellantis.
- Star Team Award for Q2, 2022 in Stellantis NV Pvt. Ltd.